How's it going everybody?
All right.
Oh, you guys are wild. This is good.
Let's get right into it. Huh? It's 2019
and my look is less ideal than ever.
Real. I Here's the deal. Uh, I am a
Jewish man, but I look like an
accountant for the Aryan Brotherhood.
And I know that
it's not good. I didn't do it on
purpose, but I do. I look like the
nerdiest guy in the worst prison gang.
It's a problem.
It's a serious pro. They're just like,
"He doesn't kill people." He does read a
lot, though. He does.
Oh, man. It's It's fine, though. People
are wild. Uh they surprise me all the
time with how wild they are. Recently, I
was in a shoe store and I was just
looking at shoes and a dude comes up to
me and he goes, "Oh, your face. That's
crazy. I can't believe you did that.
And then he goes, "Dude, so what are you
like a tattoo artist?" And I was like,
"No, man. I'm not good at art." And he
goes, "So just no job
there." Like there's no other options.
I can do work.
He's like, "Oh, so what do you do?" And
I was like, "Well, technically no job.
But still,
come on, man. And then he goes, "Well,
if you need any help with anything, you
let me know." I was like, "You work
here."
So disrespectful.
People are crazy disrespectful. I live
in New York. Dudes, this is a thing that
is happening often. Dudes who want to
get my attention in public, they will
combine what they think I look like with
prison and yell it at me.
The other day a guy was like, "Hey,
you." And I was like, and he goes,
"Yeah, you Harry Potter, but make a
prison. Come over here."
It's like, "What? I'll come over." But I
didn't like that.
This is true. The other day I was
sitting on the subway. I'm sitting
minding my business. This guy scooting
past me. He looks up at me and he stops
and he goes, "Hey, Jim from the office
did 10 years in prison. Look at you.
[Music]
did not like that one.
He's like, "That one was accurate."
Like, "Come on, man. I'm trying to grow
my hair out. Let me live my life."
People on the train were laughing. He
was killing. And he goes, "Oh, so Pam
left and you just snapped, huh?"
He has follow-ups.
[Applause]
Come on.
Yeah, just going hard.
Uh, I've been doing this, which I
shouldn't do. I've been reading comments
on my videos online. What a nightmare
online is just in general. Uh, this is
real. I've been noticing this in
comments. This is a new thing, a new
trend I've been noticing. People, uh,
usually older people will be annoyed
with my tattoos. Now, this is completely
new. They will see me and then be like,
"Gh, I remember when having your face or
your throat tattooed meant that you were
a criminal. It meant that you were
dangerous. Now it just means you're a
hipster." And I'm just like, "Are you
disappointed I'm not a murderer right
now?
What is happening?"
It's like you you assume firstly you're
making assumptions about who I am based
on how I look and then when I don't live
up to them you're like it makes no
sense. I'm furious. I cannot win with
these people. And then what's even
crazier is that I happen to have gang
tattoos on my face. I used to be a
criminal when I was younger. Not always
the case, but in my case it is.
Sometimes I will tell people that to
stop them from being annoyed with my
tattoos and then with so much confidence
they'll just tell me, "No,
no, you weren't a criminal. Listen, I've
seen The Wire and Sons of Anarchy and
you were not.
They're like experts now.
It's incredible. I spent the entire
first part of my life only wanting
respect from the scariest people you can
imagine. And now I'm on Facebook arguing
with a 40-year-old woman named Joy.
And she's just like, "I bet you've never
even stabbed anybody." What?
Like I've stabbed two people in my life.
Is this like not even three?
I bet they both survived.
[Laughter]
Oh my gosh.
These are these are the same people who
do stuff. They'll be like, "Aren't you
worried about how you're going to look
when you're older? Look at all that.
Aren't you worried about how you're
going to look when you're older?" It's
just like, "Okay, well, you're wearing
dress socks with jean shorts. Why don't
you worry about how you look right now?
How about that?
Yeah.
[Applause]
[Laughter]
Oh man. Uh let's Well, I've been
traveling a lot. Uh I've been all over.
Uh recently I was in the South and I was
at a Denny's. I was minding my own
business and I looked over and there's
like a claw machine, like one of those
giant claw machines you see, you know?
And I was like, "Oh man." And then there
was a lady in front of the claw machine.
Okay. Okay, it was a big one. Were you
being giant prizes? And she was crying
and I was like, "Wow, that seems like an
overreaction to losing that game."
And my friends were like, "No, you
idiot. Look." And I paid more attention.
And then she was crying because her
toddler had crawled into the machine.
Mhm. Mhm. And he was stuck inside of it.
And she was like, "Come out for mommy."
And he was like, "I live here now. I
have all the prizes.
Why? Why would I ever leave?
So, she's hysterical and she's just
like, "Someone call 911." Like, "Someone
call the police." And I'm just like, "M,
what? Don't waste public resources,
lady. Now is your time. Win him back.
Let's go."
Right.
The stakes have never been higher. Let's
do it.
I was just like, "Listen, I have $5. I
can claw your baby. Let me try. I can
get him. I can get him.
She did not think it was as funny as you
guys did.
So, they called they called the police
or whatever and they brought the fire
department and they took the machine
apart and got the kid out. And she was
very snoody about the whole thing. But I
was like, how funny would that have been
if just some big Italian firefighter
showed up and she was like, "What are
you going to use the jaws of life to
save my baby?" And he's like, "I have 10
ones. Let's do it.
Cut to 40 minutes later. He's like, "I'm
out of money. I am so sorry for your
loss.
Will you take a life-sized Sonic the
Hedgehog instead?"
It's It's good to be back here in the
West. Uh I live in New York now. I came
back here uh for this and to visit my
family often. Uh, it's also there's
different challenges being here than in
the city. Like for instance, recently
while I was here, I hit a deer with my
car.
Yeah, but it's not what you guys think.
Okay. I did it completely on purpose.
Now,
how how that happened was I was driving,
minding my own business, and I'm going
down the street, and I looked over and I
saw a dog and a deer in a parking lot
together. Okay? And I was like, they're
friends like in Disney.
But I was wrong. They were not friends.
They were enemies and they were fighting
pretty hard. Okay. All right. I don't
And I didn't even know the deer was
hooving the dog. I didn't even know they
did that. All right. And the dog hated
it. So the dog goes running away from
the deer to escape. And the dog comes
running across the street. I'm driving
down and the deer comes chasing after
the dog. And I had a decision to make.
Yeah,
listen. It was an Australian Shepherd.
Okay, it's crunch time.
I hit that deer so hard with my car.
I swerved in everything. Listen, I hit
that deer like my stepdad was riding it.
Do you understand?
That is what I like. a crowd that is not
a fan of my stepfather.
Nobody likes you, Joe.
I shouldn't use his real name, but
whatever.
So,
by the way, I should not say this, but
you guys seem cool, so I'm going to say
it anyway. Feels so good to hit
something that big with your car. It was
awesome.
Yes.
Listen, I didn't want to have to do it,
but if I'm going to do it, it might as
well be cool,
dude. I like I I don't know. It felt
cool to hit something that big. I get
what old people are up to in farmers
markets. I get it. I'm like, I
understand now when I'm on the couch and
I'm watching the news and they're like,
"An elderly gentleman ran over six
people and slammed his car into Best Buy
today." I'm just sitting there like,
"Live your best life, Grandpa. Get in
there."
Yeah. You didn't fight in World War II
not to hit someone with your car. Get
it.
So,
listen. I feel some of you in the
audience being worried about the deer,
and that's fair, but don't be. Okay? I
drive The Deer is fine. I drive a 2001
Saturn. The deer is fine. Okay?
Yeah,
I it seems like you guys might know a
thing or two about cars. That is not a
good car.
Uh yeah, my car is so bad that when I
bought it, I parked it on the street and
that night I assumed some kids spray
painted the word wow on the side of it
and I did not care. Okay.
Yeah. So, I'm in my 2001 Saturn. The dog
runs past. The deer is coming. I slam on
the gas. I gave it everything I had. All
that happened, okay, was the deer rolled
up onto the side of my like hood on his
side, rolled back onto its hooves and
then just looked at me like, "What was
that about, man?"
And I'm just in my car awkward like,
"Uh, I'm trying to kill you.
[Laughter]
The deer just is like, I don't I don't
need this. And it left to go do deer
stuff or whatever.
So, the deer is gone. I'm sitting in my
car. I can't believe this just happened.
And I realized the dog is nowhere to be
found. The dog escaped. Yes, I'm an
American hero.
>> Yeah, I deserve this.
[Applause]
I know. It's like the troops then me
then firefighters. I'm feeling very
good.
This is literally the most on board
anyone has ever been for that premise.
I I used to I used to put myself above
the troops even as a joke. People were
like, "Pull it back. You got to be
fine."
So,
I'm feeling good. I'm in the street. I
just hit a deer with my car. I'm a good
person. I'm feeling great.
I'm jazzed up. I'm like pumped up on a
trailer and I just can't believe that
happened. Like dancing in my car. I was
like, "Oh, I was crazy." And I look over
and I see a family.
They're wearing their Sunday best like a
mom and a dad. And they're pushing a
baby stroller down the sidewalk. And I
was like, "They probably saw everything.
They definitely want to talk to me."
So, I do a Uturn.
I pull up to them. Have you ever seen a
guy pick up a baby stroller to get away
from you faster?
Yeah.
In my car like, "What is this guy's
problem?" And then I realized, "Oh no,
they have no context for what just
happened.
They probably didn't even see the dog.
They just see some guy in the middle of
the city with his face covered in
tattoos driving the world's worst car.
Just clobber a deer for no reason.
Then that guy sits in the street and
thinks about it for a while.
spots your family,
does a Uturn,
revealing the fact that he has the word
wow spray painted
on the side of his car,
struggles to get his window down cuz he
drives a 2001 Saturn. And then he looks
out at your wife and kid and just goes,
"I'm a hero."
He left so fast.
He left his wife. He did not care.
Hustling.
Oh man.
I've been traveling a ton this year for
comedy, which has been great. Uh I went
to two places in particular. I went to
Austin and Portland. Both places. No,
hold on.
Either way, you're wrong. Both.
[Applause]
If you've seen me before and I bring up
a place, I will say nothing good about
that place.
I'm not here to be like, they were great
and moving on. No. So, I went to Austin
and Portland and they're not so bad. But
here is the thing. Austin and Portland,
both cities where their whole motto is
keep it weird. And they're we're weird.
Uh and I showed up and I'm like, I'm a
weird guy. I love weird stuff. I cannot
wait to see what I'm going to see.
Nothing weird at all. Okay. Talking to
people like when does the weird happen?
And they're like, it's around. It
wasn't.
There's nothing weird happening in
either of those places. I was like, you
guys have to the bar has to be higher. I
live in New York. Once on the subway, I
saw a guy, and this is real, only
wearing the top half of a Spongebob
costume. Okay.
Yeah. And what? Oh, what was he doing,
you ask? He was wrestling
a another man. Okay. Who clearly didn't
know him.
That guy he was wrestling was just
yelling out over and over again. He
goes, "Spong Bill, no."
Yeah,
no one on the train was helping. There's
everyone watching like he seems like he
has it under control.
So, if you're going to be weird, you got
to step it up. Also, how dare Austin and
Portland keep it weird when how how dare
they act like they're weird when they
know Florida exists?
>> Yeah. And it's just out there doing what
Florida does.
Last time I was in Florida, this is
real, by the way. This is Googleable
information. After the show, I'm in
Florida. I'm walking past a newspaper
stand. I look into the stand. The
headline on the newspaper reads, "Local
man robs Wendy's with alligator.
What did you just say to me?"
I read it. I still said that out loud.
It was incredible. Oh, and also Oh,
yeah. Yeah, that's all you want to say?
You don't want to add any more to that?
Like, I don't know. Maybe tell us if the
alligator was an accomplice or a weapon.
How about that?
For real.
Did this guy rob a Wendy's with an
alligator? Or did this guy rob a Wendy's
with an alligator?
There's a huge difference.
Like did he start a Did he start a gang
with an alligator, throw a bandana on
it? He's like, "We're the alligator boys
now.
Let's get to a Wendy's and make this
official."
No.
So, this is how I I bought the paper and
I read the article and this is real. He
used the alligator as a weapon. Okay.
And when I read that, I was like, "Did
he at least hold it like a gun?"
Right. He didn't. He threw it
through a drivethru window.
Yep.
Didn't see that one coming, did you?
You know who else didn't? The lady
at the drivethru.
So many things have to happen before you
can even throw an alligator.
You have to find it in the wild.
Also, by the way, how horrible is
Florida that there is just alligators
available to you?
What was even his qualifying material?
Was he looking for a specific type or
did he just the first one he saw he was
like this is the one and he took it.
That was it.
So this is real. This happened in
Florida. A place connected to the United
States
where we are all living currently.
A grown man with a driver's license
found an alligator that day. He didn't
even build a relationship with it.
Takes his new alligator and he seat
belts it into the back seat of his car.
I assume.
I just have no idea how else you keep it
from getting into the front seat and
biting you, right?
I don't
I don't know if you guys know anything
about alligators, but they kind of just
do whatever they want.
So he seat belts this dinosaur into the
back seat
and he gets into the front seat and he's
like, "Ah, I got to make some money
today."
Star the wheel. I could get a job. And
he goes, "No, no time.
Spent most my day on that alligator
thing
projects.
I could rob someone. He goes, I could
rob a place cuz places have more money
than someone's.
Rob a bank. And he goes, no, no, they'll
be expecting that.
He's thinking about it. And then he
thought, he comes to the conclusion,
Wendy's.
They have money and chili. That's the
place.
So he drives his new alligator to
Wendy's. Okay. Pulls up to the
drive-thru and the lady at the
drive-thru is like, "Hello, how can I
help you today?" And he goes, "Give me
all the money." And she just goes, looks
right at him and goes, "Uh, no.
You didn't even come inside.
You failed at this robbery." And the
dude is so mad. He goes, "Give me the
money in the register or I'll kill you."
And she's from Florida, so she's not
afraid of death or whatever.
She looks down at him. She's like, "No,
if you had a gun, you would have shown
it to me already. I call your bluff. Get
out of here, crazy guy. Go, go, go."
He's seething mad at this point,
furious. And he's like, "You know what?
I don't have a gun, but hold on."
And then he palmed an alligator
through the drive-thru window.
Yuck.
He skipped so many steps in that
robbery.
If he had a list of things
he was supposed to do, he would have
thrown the alligator, looked down, and
just been like, "Oh no,
I was supposed to threaten her with the
alligator first.
[Laughter]
By the way, can you imagine being her
telling this guy off and he's like, "You
know what? I don't have a gun." And
you're like, "Wow, nailed it. Really
doing it today." And then he leans back
and starts unbuckling the world's
ugliest toddler.
Like, hey, someone come and see this is
wild. And then you look back and an
alligator is flying.
Imagine being the car behind him.
just
sitting there with your girlfriend like
what takes so long to make burgers here.
She's on her phone. You're like, "Do you
even care?" You look back from her and
then an alligator soarses
from window to window.
Honey, get off your phone. They're
throwing alligators into Wendy's.
This guy is crazy.
She's on her phone like, "That doesn't
make sense. They don't even serve
alligators here.
What? Why am I with you?"
[Laughter]
So, this dude is sitting there awkwardly
with no more alligators left to play in
the robbery,
probably thinking to himself, "Oh, you
think if I ask for my alligator back?
Such a bad idea to throw it. He didn't
even put a fanny pack on it. Like maybe
get some money while you're in there. I
don't know.
So
he drives off.
Yeah. And he gets arrested immediately.
He didn't even wear a mask.
Yeah. He was like, "I'm in Florida.
People throw alligators. I'll probably
get lost in the shuffle."
Uh, no, he didn't. They remembered him.
They arrested him pretty hard
afterwards.
The end of the article is true. It goes,
"No one was injured. The alligator was
safely released back into the wild." And
the very end of the article, it read,
"No drug involvement suspected."
Oh, yeah. Florida, that was your sober
plan.
What does the nonsober plan look like?
Do you ride a horse and the alligator
throws you? What happens?
I make fun of alligator guy like I have
my life together, but I don't.
I There's no easy way to say this, but
my life it's not it's not together. My
personal life isn't as good as you think
it might be. And some of you were like,
Shane, your life has to be going well.
Look at you on stage. Yeah, I'm living
my dreams and that's nice, but also my
personal life chatters. Let me tell you,
okay, there's no easy way to say this,
so I'm just going to open up and say it.
Okay, I am 32 years old and I pooped my
pants recently. Okay.
Yep. Not supposed to do that.
Uh
[Music]
I don't like the way some of you are
laughing, by the way.
Like you just to clarify, I didn't just
do it like I wasn't just like watching
Batman like, "Duh, this movie is good. I
don't think I'm going to make it." Like
I didn't poop my pants freestyle for the
love of the game.
I had a reason
here. Here's what happened. Okay. I had
food poisoning.
Yeah, it could happen to anybody. I had
food poisoning. I was parallel parking
my car.
That's not a part of this. That's mostly
a humble brag, but I can parallel park
my car. So, I'm parking my car. I had
food poisoning and I coughed.
Yep. And it happened to me.
I pooped my pants. Listen, you know how
sometimes you fart and you're like,
"That was pretty gross, but I'm okay."
Not that one.
Nope. I I pooped my pants so fast and so
hard. It was like somebody else pooped
my pants.
It was incredible.
By the way, didn't even know that was
one of the options when you cough.
What? That can happen.
I've been pooping my pants for 32 years.
Did I say pooping my pants? I meant
coughing.
Cut that one. Cut that in post.
Everybody
[Applause]
go ahead and cut that one out. Okay,
listen. Bye.
You guys don't know my life.
I've been coughing for 32 years.
Not once ever. After coughing for 32
years I ever been like, whoa,
what was that? One of my friends is
like, what just happened? I was like, I
coughed. I almost pooped my pants. He's
like, yeah, that can happen. Got to
watch out for those.
Not once ever.
Like the cough waited 32 years and then
betrayed me.
Like once I was in ninth grade and I was
giving a talk in front of the class and
I coughed and my body was like, "Do we
do it now?"
And then puberty was like, "No, we will
embarrass him.
You hold back. Wait 20 years, then take
him out right before he has to do
comedy."
Yeah. I was parking at a comedy club.
It was worst case. So, I'm like, get out
of my car. I can't get back into it.
It's not one of those.
I was like, what do I what do I do?
And I was like, my first plan was to buy
the pants off of a homeless guy.
But they are never there when you need
them, the homeless.
My second plan was to buy the shirt off
of a guy wearing two shirts. But here's
the thing. If you try and buy the shirt
off of a guy wearing two shirts and you
tell him you need it cuz he pooped your
pants, he will run from you. So, I was
going to wear it like a I don't know
what I thought. Anyway, so I look across
the street and there's like a mall and I
was like, I got to get over there. So, I
waddle over, you know.
Yeah, it's a shameful walk. People can
tell they can't. A kid tries to talk to
me and his dad is like, get away from
him.
And his kid is like because of how he
looks. And he's like, "No, other things.
Go
get away."
So,
I get into the first clothing store I
can get into and the guy working there
is like, "Hello. How can we help you
today?" I was like, "Come here. Come
here right now."
And he's like, "Oh, what's going on?
What What is it?" And I was like,
"Here's the deal, man. I have fully
pooped my pants."
And he just goes, "Excuse me?" It's
like, am I stuttering right now, Daniel?
Okay,
I need you on TV, right? There's no
time. Do they not train you for this?
He's like, "What do I do?" I was like,
"Go get me a pair of jeans this second."
So, he runs off and he comes back and he
goes, "I have mediums and I have
larges." And I was like, "Give me the
mediums." And then he looks right at me
and he goes, "Do you want to try those
on?"
Like, "Do you think this is a game,
Daniel?
[Music]
I need the key to your employee bathroom
in an undisclosed amount of time. Man,
how many times you going to make me say
it? I have pooped my pants.
In a weird twist of fate, I am wearing
those pants currently.
Thank you so much, everyone. Have a
great night.
Yeah. Okay.
I'm going to I feel like I don't deserve
that. I'm going to be honest with you
guys. It's good though. Thank you so
much. I'm uh I'm happy to be here. I
feel some of you are like, "Okay, what's
going on with this guy?" You know,
are we at a show or are we being robbed?
You know, you are at a show, but you
might also be getting robbed. Time will
tell. Okay. I uh let's talk about me for
a moment. We'll start with some basics.
Uh I live across the street from a
7-Eleven. All right.
It's not funny yet, but okay. Cool.
I uh I drink a lot of Mountain Dew,
okay? It's like my only vice. I drink a
lot of Mountain Dew. I'm in that
7-Eleven constantly drinking Mountain
Dew. Okay. Getting refills. I'm in there
so often that everyone who works in that
7-Eleven. They have a nickname for me.
When they see me, they call me Mountain
Dew Guy. Yeah. Do you guys know how much
Mountain Dew I have to drink not to have
the nickname throat tattoo guy?
It is
a lot. The
It's so much Mountain Dew, you guys.
It's a lot. It's a For me to walk in a
7-Eleven and the guy to be like,
"Mountain Dew guy." And the new guy who
works here to be like, "Not throat or
face tattoo guy.
He drinks more Mountain Dew than the
fact that he ruined his life by
tattooing his face." And the guy's like,
"Yeah, what aren't you getting about
this?" you know. Yeah. Uh I also know it
was a bad idea to tattoo my face just so
we're all on the same page. Okay.
Yeah. Yeah. I uh I when I tattooed my fa
I well I didn't when I got my face
tattooed
when I got my face tattooed I was like
there will be positives and there will
be negatives. You know I'm going to be
honest with you guys. It has been mostly
negatives so far. Okay,
I can't even think of one positive. I'm
going to be real with you guys. Uh, so
I'm here to make you laugh tonight, but
I'm also here to say if some of you are
thinking about tattooing your face,
probably don't. Okay,
I saw I saw some of you come in and I
don't think you could handle it. All
right, it's not
could not hack it. It's It's rough out
here. Uh,
all my tattoos are real. I shouldn't
have to say that, but sometimes after
shows I meet people and they're like,
"Wow, crazy, man. You look crazy. Are
those all real?" And I have to be like,
"What? What are you talking about right
now? Of course they're real. What do you
think I drew all these on today?
I just wake up every day and draw these
on? Like, what would I stand to gain
from drawing fake tattoos on my throat
and face?
I just wake up every morning and I'm
drawing them on like, you know what? I
just want old people to be afraid of me.
That's what I'm about, you know? I just
wake up every day and draw tattoos on my
fingers. Like, I just want to struggle
in job interviews. You know,
one one time after a show, a lady comes
up to me and she's like, "Don't be so
hard on yourself." And I'm like, "Thank
you so much. Will you give me a job?"
and she was like, "It's nice meeting
you.
Come back. I need work. I uh
I travel a lot for this job. This is my
only job, which is probably not good."
But you know what? I'm I travel a lot
and people in other places, they're like
pretty cool. Not very many people care
about my tattoos. Uh I live here in
Utah. I got to say, uh some of you are
not on board. Okay.
I have a lot of weird experiences here
that don't happen anywhere else. I'll
give you an example. Once I got done
with a show, uh I'm here in Utah. I get
done with a show and an older gentleman
comes up to me afterwards. So old. So so
old. You guys, have you ever have you
ever seen someone so old that if they
were getting in the driver's side of a
car, you'd be like, "Uh, is anybody else
seeing this right now?" You know, do I
have to stop? Am I the one? you know,
how how close are we to a farmers
market? Like,
what is the danger level here is what?
And he's so old. And he comes right up
to me and he he goes, "Hey, man. I love
your comedy. Good job staying off the
streets.
I don't even know what that means."
Okay. Off the What? Where did you learn
how to talk like that? What are you the
coolest guy at your retirement home? You
know, he's just like, "I'm the Tupac of
my friend group." Like, what?
Just assumes I'm gangster cuz I have
lots of tattoos. I am not gangster.
That's not how it works at all. Okay.
I'm the least gangster person ever. I
cry at the end of Toy Story 3 like
everybody else. Okay.
[Applause]
That guy cried so hard. All right. You
know, me and him, a lot of crying. Okay.
And yeah, man. It's not gangster. It
just makes no sense. I got done. Here's
another thing. I'm at a grocery store. I
get in line behind this lady. Just a
regular lady. Nothing going on. She
doesn't notice me get in line behind
her. She's standing there. She turns
around. She sees me and she makes this
noise. She goes and then she left.
She just left
[Applause]
with all her stuff.
Like, yeah. Uh, pretty sure she's
stealing right now. Is anybody
Is is anybody else watching her? You
know, they were not. Uh yeah. So, I'm
pretty sure she got away with like a lot
of free stuff. Uh
oh, man.
I don't know. You guys would be
surprised to know though, despite all
the weird interactions I have with
people who like are weird about my
tattoos or don't know what it's like to
have tattoos, the weirdest interactions,
my least favorite interactions are
always with other people who are heavily
tattooed. Not a fan of other heavily
tattooed people. Okay. Yeah, I'm calling
it. It's not good. I know everything I
need to know about another guy with a
lot of tattoos. You know, your parents
hit you. School was hard. You like to
bring a snake to the park, you know.
I get it. You know, I don't want to have
these weird conversations with guys.
It's terrible. I'll give you an example.
Okay, I'm at Walmart. I'm standing in
line. Everything's going fine. I'm in
line a lot in my jokes, so just keep
going with that. But I'm in I'm in line.
I'm standing there. I look over and I
see this guy wearing a tank top and he's
bald head completely covered in black
and gray tattoos. His entire head is
like covered in flames. He's got skulls
and stuff. Obviously, he got all these
tattoos in prison. Okay, I feel some of
you being awkward. He's not here. We're
safe. All right.
Also, I'm allowed to make the judgment
call. All right.
So, I see him. He sees me and we make
eye contact and it's locked in for a
second and immediately I'm like, "Oh no,
this guy's going to try to talk to me."
You know, have you ever just seen
someone in public who's going to talk to
you and they're just so white trash you
don't have the energy to deal with them?
So many crazy people. So this guy, he
comes up to me, all right, this dude at
Walmart covered in his statues. He comes
up to me. His opening line to me, the
first thing he says, he goes, "Hey man,
where'd you do your time?"
What? I've done zero time, everyone.
I've never been to jail a day in my
life. Okay, this guy's but he's like
he's just making an assumption about me.
He's trying to connect with me and I was
like, you know what? I'm going to
connect with him. I'll meet him halfway.
I'll just mess with him a little. So, I
was like, you know how it is, man. Did 5
years in Asaban. No big deal.
Yeah.
Yep. He He wanted to impress me so bad.
He was like, "Word. All right. Cool.
Cool."
like all that time in prison and you
didn't read one Harry Potter book
seems seems kind of like a waste, you
know? I don't know what he's up to now,
but I'm pretty sure it's not reading.
So,
it's not not good.
Oh, man. I'm super glad you guys laughed
at that.
Super glad. I have told that joke before
and gotten zero. I I did a show in
Wyoming once. By the way, Wyoming, a
dumpster fire pretending to be a state.
Don't know if you guys
knew that. It is It is It is one big
Walmart parking lot. It is not good.
There's nothing there. Why are you there
anyway? Doesn't matter.
I'm in I'm in Wyoming. I'm in this tiny
town doing a show to like this many
people. It's a pretty big audience. All
right. And I say that line. I say
Asaban. Complete silence. All right. No,
I'm just like, "Oh, okay. So, y'all
don't read. That makes so much sense."
You know,
it's rough. And then out of nowhere, a
lady in the front row yells so loud. She
goes, "Why do you go there?
What? What are you saying? I the what?
How? How?" The first part of that joke,
I say, "I've never been to jail a day in
my life. It's not even a real place.
Prison for wizards. Why are we Why are
we having this conversation?"
And then she and then she goes, "It is a
real place. That's that place in San
Francisco."
Nope. Nope. That is not correct. Okay.
You you are thinking of Alcatraz, okay,
which has been closed for like 50 years.
So, you're not even right if you were
right. I don't,
you know, and then the audience is like
on her side for no re It's just so
weird. It's the weirdest experience. And
then and then she says, "Agree to
disagree."
Like, that's not how that it's not how
anything works. What?
Why is this happening to me right now?
And one guy in the audience was like,
she got you though. And I was like, she
didn't though. She did not. No one got
anyone. She's so wrong. You know, I
wanted to be so mean to that audience,
but I was like, they live in Wyoming, so
punish,
you know,
the punishment fits the crime. Really?
So bad. So awful. So yeah, don't go
there. I don't know. It's not good. I
shouldn't I talk bad in Wyoming like I
have my life together. I do not. Uh as
my life is a complete disaster. I
sneezed on a baby recently. Yeah, that's
a thing I did. I was holding a baby and
I had to sneeze and I just hard sneezed
into its face so hard, you know, and my
friend is standing there. He's like,
"Hey man, uh real quick, uh did you just
sneeze in my son's face?"
And I was like, "Yeah, yeah, I did
that." Yep. And he was like, "Why?" And
I was like, "Well, I'm I have the baby."
And I was like, "I got to sneeze." So, I
could I was like, "I could drop the baby
or I could sneeze on this baby right
now." You know, those are my two
options. And he was like, "Why? You
could turn your head and sneeze the
other way." And I was like, "That third
option was not apparent at the time. You
know,
it just didn't occur to me in the
moment." He's like, "You need help." I
was like, "I do though." You know, I'm
at least I'm not from Wyoming. I have
that going for me.
I get it from my mom. She's a crazy
person. Does anyone else relate to that?
She's a wild woman. All right, those
people get it. And so my mom, she's
Here's a thing that happened recently. I
laughed at my mom so hard in public that
she started yelling at me. You know,
here's the backstory. Have you ever, by
the way, laughing so hard like falling
down in the aisle at the grocery store?
And I laughed. Here's what happened. She
told me her dog had diabetes. Okay. And
I started laughing so hard. No, it's so
fat. Of course it does. You know, it's
so big. And she was like, it's not
funny. How could I have known he has
diabetes? And I'm like, probably cuz he
looks like a propane tank with legs.
That's how you know the there were so
many clues. He's huge. Of course, he's
diabetic. And then also you feed him
people food all the time. I caught her
feeding him Doritos Locos tacos from
Taco Bell once. It's like why are you
why are you feeding him the more
expensive tacos? You know
she this is true. She goes he prefers
them. Like what did he tell you that?
What is happening here? Also he's a
Chihuahua. We get it. You know, it's
ridiculous. My mom, so we're we're a
Jewish family. She names a dog Masleto,
okay? She's telling me about him getting
diagnosed. She takes him to the vet.
She's going to these crazy vets who like
talks to their animals like they're
patients, you know? So, he's like
sitting there with my mom and the dog.
He looks him the dog right in his stupid
fat diabetic face. Okay. No one feel bad
for him. He's not here. We can make fun
of him. Also, he's a dog. He has no idea
what's happening at all times. Okay.
So, she looks or the the vet looks right
at him and goes, "Maseltov, you have
diabetes."
Like, that
is incorrect. That
seems anti-Semitic. I know it's not, but
it felt like it
when she told the story.
She's out of control. She bought a
computer recently. She wouldn't let me
help her set it up. And then like an
hour after she bought it, she calls me
and she's like, "Hey, I'm locked out of
my computer. I can't get in. Can you get
into my computer for me?" I'm like, "I
can't get into your computer." "What do
you mean? You're having trouble." And
she's like, "Yeah, I don't remember my
password." I was like, "Just you're
going to have to remember it. I don't
know how to get into your computer for
you." So, she gets mad. She hangs up on
me. She calls me back like half an hour
later. She's like, "Didn't need your
help." Got back into my computer. I'm
like a hacker.
No, no, mom. You're the opposite of a
hacker. Okay. You You forgot Caps Lock
was on. That is not what a hacker is.
You know,
I'm a hacker. No. False.
So bad. I don't know. I talk bad. I have
no right to talk bad about my mom though
beyond sneezing on a baby. I'm like
really bad at everything. I re I don't
even know how debt works. I recently
found that out when my dentist sent me
to collections.
Yeah, my dentist sent me to collections.
The collection agency calls my phone. I
answer cuz I don't know who it is. And
they're like, "Hey, we're trying to
collect a debt. Give us the money." And
I was like, "Uh, no. You know, no, I'm
just not going to." And he's like,
"What?" And I was like, "What are the
consequences if I don't give you money?"
And he was like, "We're going to make
your credit bad." And I was like, "Not
possible."
Yeah. My credit's already really bad. My
credit score is so bad it also has face
tattoos. Do you guys
It's so bad. It's I've been denied for a
Best Buy card. Do you know what that
that's I've seen a bird accidentally fly
into Best Buy and leave with a card.
It's so easy to get one. When I got
denied, the guy in in the Best Buy was
like, "I'm so sorry. This has never
happened before." Like, he was
embarrassed for me, you know? It was so
bad. It was so bad. And so, I like tried
to get a cell phone once and they were
like, "It's a $1,000 deposit and then
we'll let you buy a phone." I was like,
"I will leave here with two tin cans in
string." Okay, that's so much money. I
don't have that money. So, anyway, my
credit's really bad. It's It's like, so
I'm not worried about it. So I'm like,
"Well, do you have another thing?"
Telling the debt collector like,
"Listen, I'm not worried. Do you have
another thing?" And he's like, "We don't
have another thing." And I was like,
"Well, I'm going to go ahead and not pay
you then. I'm going to choose that
option." And he was like, "This has
never happened before."
It's like, "Well, you know, it was a
first time for everything, so I'm going
to go ahead and hang up now." And he's
like, "Have a good day, I guess." You
know, we're all very confused. It was a
lot of first times for everyone, you
know. So, we both hang up the phone. I
call my dentist. I'm like, "Hey, why'd
you send me to collections?" And the
front desk lady answers it, by the way.
And she's like a hundred years old and
her name is Gertrude because of course,
you know, everyone named everyone a
hundred years or older has a name like
Gertrude. And I'm like, "Why are you
even working there? You've been out of
the teeth game forever." You know, she's
so rude. No one feel bad for Gertude.
Okay. She's so rude. And I'm like,
"Why'd you send me to collections? Why
don't you just call me and ask me to pay
the bill?" And she's like, "I sent you
letters." I was like, "Yeah, and I threw
them away like an adult. You know, I'm
not I'm not reading your letters,
Gertrude. I'm not your sweetheart from
World War II." Okay. No one reads
letters in 2017.
Text me anything else. You know, so
she's like, "I don't know what to tell
you. You're already at collections." And
I was like, "All right. Well, I guess I
have to find a new dentist. That's
weird." So, you know, that happened. So,
turns out, by the way, collection
agencies call me all the time. And I'm
just like, listen, do you have another
thing? And they're like, "This is our
only thing." And then I'm like, "Well,
I'm going." And I hang up. You know,
it's a repeating process. Well, it turns
out collection agencies do have another
thing. They have one more thing. They
can they can send someone to serve you
papers to take you to small claims court
to get that money. Okay? But here's the
thing about serving someone papers. to
serve them papers to bring you to court.
They have to get you to admit you are
who you are. Okay.
So, it's like 3:00 in the afternoon one
day and I hear a knock at my door and I
answer the door and it's this guy
standing there with a clipboard and he's
like, "Hey, are you Shane Smith?" And I
was like, "No, never. What? What's going
on?" And he's like, "Uh, does Shane
Smith live here?" And I was like, "I
don't know. Pretty big place. Never seen
anyone by that name here, you know." He
was like, "Uh, looks like a very small
apartment. Actually, it's like you're
splitting hairs right now, guy. You
know, what are you trying to insult me?
What's going on?" And that's when I
realized he's standing there with a
clipboard and on that clipboard is my
Facebook profile printed out on it. So,
he's seeing me see him looking down at
me with my stupid tattooed face on the
clipboard,
looking right back up at him, seeing me
see him. I think I said that right. And
it's so it's so awkward. And he's like,
"Okay, well, if you're not Shane Smith,
who are you?" And it's like 3 p.m. I had
just woken up. I'm not ready to be
someone else. You know, I just said the
first name that came to mind. I was
like, "Uh, Bruce Wayne. I'm Bruce
Wayne."
He was not impressed. You know, in
hindsight, I could have thought of a
better name. So, he's standing there
looking very defeated. And that's when I
realize I am wearing Batman pajamas.
Yeah, not good. And I was like, so I was
like, uh, is this your only thing? And
he was like, yeah, man. This is my only
thing. And I was like, so I'm going to
go now.
And he was like, have a good day, I
guess. It's like, all right. So, I'm
pretty sure that's going to work itself
out. You know, there are no
consequences. I don't know if you guys
knew that. No consequences to debt.
Like, what are they going to do? Send me
to Alcatraz? Can't.
It's been close. Thank you.
It's been closed for like 50 years. Yes.
Oh man, I uh not good with people. Saw a
lady recently crying in the middle of
the aisle at Target. Just in the middle
of ugly crying. Hard crying. Okay. And I
was like, "Oh no, I should do
something." So I'm in Target. I get
myself ready. She's crying so hard. I go
right up to her and I'm like, "Excuse
me, ma'am. Uh, I think you mean to be in
Walmart right now. So,
nailed that interaction. Yeah.
How about How about don't cry in Target,
Karen. Okay. I'm not paying an extra 15
cents for macaroni and cheese to see you
cry.
Target is for champions. Okay.
Ridiculous.
[Music]
So bad. so so bad. My friends are so
dumb.
I know a lot of dumb people. There's a
lot of dumb people who live in my
neighborhood. This is a thing that
happened to me recently. I'm walking
around. I see all these people gather
around a tree. They're all like around
this tree. I'm like, "What is this?" And
I walk up and they're like, they're all
standing there and I see one guy and he
goes, "Hey man, there's a cat stuck up
on the top of this tree. Look at you
with all your tattoos. You're not afraid
of anything. Why don't you climb up and
get it down?"
Uh, that's not how tattoos work, guy.
Okay.
Yeah. Yeah. You don't tattoo the fear
out of people.
That's not a thing. That's never been a
thing. No one's like getting a tattoo
and the tattoo artist is like, "How does
it feel?" And the guy's like, "Oh, it
hurts real bad, but I don't care about
sharks anymore." You know,
silly.
Cat's probably still up there. I don't
know. You know, it's ridiculous. I'm
afraid of tons of stuff. So many things,
you know, spiders at the very top of the
list of things I'm afraid of, right? Can
I get some backup? Spiders are scary.
Thank you.
My idiot friends, they're like, "Hey,
man. Why are you afraid of spiders?
You're 90% more likely to be killed by a
vending machine than a spider." Like,
what are you talking about right now?
I'm not afraid of spiders cuz I think
they're going to kill me. They're
creepy. I don't want them on me or near
me. You know, you're so dumb. You know
what? I'll be worried about vending
machines the way I'm worried about
spiders when vending machines start
using spiders tactics. Okay? When I open
my shower curtain to take a sh a shower
and there's a vending machine inside
waiting to tip over on top of me, I'll
start worrying about it. All right. When
I'm like playing video games and I have
to tell my friend to look out because a
vending machine is descending above him
on a web,
you know, then we'll start worrying.
You imagine it crushes him. The
paramedics come and they're like, "We're
sorry we couldn't save him. We're so so
sorry for your loss." Doritos. Like, no,
man.
So dumb. 90% more likely. Like, what? No
one ever. That doesn't make sense. Why?
How are you drawing that parallel? No
one ever got killed by a spider cuz they
bought a Butterfinger from it and it
wouldn't give it up. You know, that's
never happened. How about this
statistic? 100% of people killed by
vending machines are morons. How about
that? You know,
[Applause]
I'm always I've been telling that joke
for a while and I'm always afraid I'm
going to tell that joke one time and
there's going to be one person in the
audience who's like, "My husband was
crushed by a vending machine." Now I'm
going to be like, "Oh no." But it was
pretty funny though, right?
Spiders. So scary. Eight-legged
nightmare factories. You know, it's not
good. The only thing worse than a
spider, people have spiders as pets.
What is happening there? You maniacs.
You know, I hate it so much. And they
always say dumb stuff, too. Spiders are
more afraid of you than you are of them.
False. Not real. Nope. No spider is more
afraid of me than I am of it. Okay? No
spider has ever caught me in bed and
been like, "Well, I am sleeping in the
living room tonight.
That's never happened. No, no spider has
ever seriously considered burning its
apartment down cuz it found me, you
know.
That's never happened. No spider's ever
been peeing in the middle of the night.
And then I ran past it and it peed all
over itself. Okay,
that joke is so much more real than I
want it to be. It's
Oh man,
this is my job now. This is my job. But
I used to have a day job. I used to have
a day job working with disabled kids.
That's true. And here's a real thing.
You've never been insulted until a kid
with autism insults you. Yeah. Yeah.
I'll give you an example. Working with
this kid, this 11-year-old kid, he's
autistic. One of my favorite clients I
ever worked with. Loved this guy. Okay.
He's like, "Hey, I want to go to the
mall. I want to go to the Lego store.
Will you take me?" I was like, "Yeah,
man. I'll take you." So, I'm driving him
to the Lego store. Okay. I'm having a
terrible day. He can totally tell. It's
written all over my face. Okay, it's the
only thing that's not. And I'm I'm,
you know, I'm having So, I'm having this
terrible day and he can tell and he
wants to cheer me up. So, this little
kid, he looks over at me, puts his hand
on my shoulder, and he goes, "Shane,
you're the coolest person I know." And
then he looks out the window and he
goes, "I got to meet more people."
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And to this day, I don't know if he was
being mean or if that was the autism.
What was that? What? So, I left him at
the Lego store. You know, he's their
problem now.
All right, you guys. I'm going to tell
you one more story and then we're going
to get out of here. Cool.
>> Good. You guys have been great. Thank
you so much for coming out. This is
good.
All right,
last story. Last story coming down the
pipe. Now, this one's going to get a
little weird. I need you all to stay on
board. The payoff is worth it. Okay? I
promise you, it's going to get real
weird. Stay with me, okay? Now, here's
the deal. I before I worked with kids, I
was a professional criminal. I was a
gang member for about 4 years. That's
true. And I know some of you were like,
"What? Earlier in the act, you said you
weren't a gangster." Well, yeah. That's
the first rule of the streets. Trust
nobody. Okay. Yeah, that's true. I was a
gang member. And when I tell people
that, a lot of the time they're like,
"Whoa, were you a [__] or were you a
blood?" And I'm like, "That's not how it
works. You don't just go out for the big
gangs like it's a college or something,
you know? No one's like, I want to be a
blood, but the Latin Kings are my safety
gang." You know,
you don't you don't try to be in a gang.
It just happens to you. Usually, you're
in denial. People are like, "I think
you're a criminal." And you're like,
"There's no way I'm a criminal. I work
at Hot Topic." Okay? There's no way.
There's no way. You know, Tupac was
never like, "Oh no, I'm late for my
shift at the mall." And then left. You
know, that's not how it works. But
eventually it sneaks up on you and
you're kidnapping someone for for money.
And you're telling your friend like,
"How cool is it? We're making money to
do this. Oh, that's right. I'm a
criminal now. Okay, cool." You know, it
gets serious fast. Also, you guys, no
one be awkward. It's not what you think.
It was just mostly like violent crimes
and robberies and stuff. Okay.
So
during this time when I was a criminal,
all right, I had a best friend. Now his
name was Angry Anton.
Not a clever nickname. All right, just
an angry guy. You know, sometimes you
meet people and they're like nickname is
little John, but they're 7 feet tall and
you're like, "Oh, that's cute." It was
not that. Okay. It was just laz lazy
nicknaming. He was just angry all the
time. He was very scary. He was bigger
than me. He was way more heavily
tattooed than me. And I know a lot of
you are like, "How is it even possible
to be more heavily tattooed than you?"
His entire face was completely covered.
100%. So, he's basically like if you got
a second grader and you pulled him to
the side and you're like, "Draw me what
you think a murderer looks like." And
then they drew him and you'd be like,
"That is way correct. That's so correct.
That's so scary. Where are your
parents?" You know, he's so scary. Just
a few stories to like reiterate how
scary he is. Once we were at a
restaurant and we were in the bathroom
and in this particular restaurant, they
had like an area where all their
toiletries were where you could just get
to them and we were stealing them, okay?
Cuz you know, we just we wanted
toiletries. We're not going to pay for
them. So, we have a backpack and we're
stuffing like toilet paper and soap and
all this stuff. We're stealing. A
uniformed police officer walks into the
bathroom while we're stealing, sees us.
Anton stands up, says, "What's up?" to
the police officer, and the police
officer said, "Excuse me." Closed the
door and left the restaurant.
Yeah. Yeah. Anyway, eventually I was
like, I got to get out. And so when you
get out, the government helps you.
Usually you have to cut ties with your
friends, your family, everybody who has
any tie to that lifestyle. Okay? and
move on. And usually the government will
give you a job to help you move on
before so that you don't end up in
prison. Sometimes the government lets
you work with disabled kids. All right.
Yeah, I know. They should change that.
So anyway,
it worked out for me, but I feel like
maybe not so much for other people. And
so
I have this new job. I have this new
life. Now, uh, Anton was a bad person.
Objectively, yes, I agree with all of
you. He was a bad person, but also he
was always good to me. He was a loyal
friend. I'd known him forever. I
couldn't get rid of him. I kept him
around in my life just a little bit.
Just talking to him through emails,
being his friend, okay? Trying to be
there for him. So, I'm moving on with
this new life. It's like a year later,
and I'm working at this facility for
disabled kids. Okay. Now, working at
this facility, I worked with a lot of
Christian people. I'll worked with a lot
of LDS people, Mormon people, and
they're all like really jazzed up to
work with me. All these upright good
people and then me, you know, and
they're just like, "Oh man, isn't Shane
cool knowing about my past?" Like, he
says the sword sometimes,
crazy, you know? So, they're way jazzed
up to work with me and it's going pretty
well. Now, at work, there's this guy
named Mike. Okay? Now, Mike had a
weekend job working at a summer camp.
Okay? And one day, Mike comes up to me
and he's like, "Hey, I work at this
camp." All right? And we just barely got
this group of new kids, this new program
we're doing. Now, these are kids that
are going down the same path you went
down when you were a kid. Okay? They're
making all the same mistakes, and
they're going down the same path. Would
you like to come give them a talk, maybe
try and set them straight, make them
work out, do like some boot camp stuff,
and just trying to like teach them the
right ways to do things? And I'm like,
"Yeah, man. anything to keep kids from
going down the same road I went down,
you know, anything to stop kids from
doing the gang life. And he's like, "All
right, and if there's anyone you want to
bring with you to help, let me know."
And I was like, "I know just the guy."
Okay. Yeah. Yeah. So, it's the weekend
and we show up to work with these kids
and he's like, "Hey, the counselor who
normally normally works with these kids
isn't here, but the kids are in this
barn." So, he brings me and Anton to
this barn. Okay. Yeah. All these kids
are there and they do not look happy.
And he's like, "These are the kids. I'm
going to go down the way and like play
guitar or do whatever, do crafts. I
don't know what he did, you know." And
he's like, "I'm going to do this now.
You guys are going to talk to these
kids, make them work out, set them
straight." And we were like, "Oh, we got
this." So he leaves and immediately we
start laying into these kids, okay? We
are saying a lot of things to these
kids. We're yelling at them. One of them
looks Anton in the face and he's like,
"If you make eye contact with me again,
I will pluck yours out and eat them."
Yeah. I was like, "Whoa, too. Where you
leave yourself nowhere to go from there,
you know? Where you can't just open up?
I'll eat your eyes. That's too much. You
have nowhere else to go." You know? So,
we're just yelling at these kids. We're
screaming them. We're making them work
out. They're doing push-ups. They are
not pumped. It's like 2004. So, we find
the kid with like the puka shell
necklace. He's the leader. We're just
we're really giving it to him, you know.
And so eventually one of these kids
stands up and he's like, "I'm not doing
another push-up." And we're like, "Uh,
you know, you are going to do one." And
Anton gets right in his face and he
says, "Do push-ups or consequences." And
the kid says, "My parents will sue you."
So a couple minutes later, he's choking
this kid right so hard. He's choking so
And so all the other kids are freaking
out now.
And they're just like, "Shane, do
something. Stop." And I'm like, "What?
So I can get choked, too? No way." You
know, I'm He's done this to himself. So
now,
so now everyone's doing push-ups.
They're doing so many push-ups. Okay.
They're so scared. And now people are
crying so much. There's crying a lot.
Way too much. And I'm just like, these
gangster kids are like, all of them are
crying so much snot. And I'm just like,
"We could see you crying. like get it
together, you know, you're embarrassing.
And that's when I'm like, what is with
all these kids crying and like parents
sue you? Bad kids don't have parents.
And then I'm like, so I'm like, I got to
figure something out. So I'm like,
Anton, are you going to be okay alone
with these kids? And he's like, I got
it.
Cool. So I go down the way to talk to
Mike. I'm like, hey, Mike, what's going
on? Uh, nothing weird going on back
there. Uh, you want to tell me some more
about these kids? how they're going down
the wrong path, the same path I went
down. And he's like, "Yeah, man. These
are just kids that are like not
listening to their parents. Some of them
fell asleep in church, you know,
sloughing class." I'm like, "Oh, okay.
Uh, cool.
I'm going to go now." Yeah. Not gang
members, just moderately bad Mormons.
Okay.
These kids are not. They're not ready
for the heat we are bringing. Okay. I
thought they were like hardened killers.
They're so soft. These are just soft
white kids. I don't I'm so worried. And
then I have left them alone
with Anton. Grown men shouldn't be alone
with him. I'm running back to the barn.
Okay. I practically kick open the door.
Inside the barn, everyone is shirtless
for no reason. Okay.
All the kids have formed a circle and in
that circle, two kids are fighting to
the death thunderdome style,
hard crying. Anton is just egging him
on. And I'm like, "Dude, shut it down."
Like, it's up. What is happening? Like
all the kids in the corner and he's
like, "What's going on?" And I'm like,
"Get these kids over here." And he's
like, "Talk to me. What's going on,
man?" And I was like, "Dude, we are
we're in so much trouble. Like, dude,
we're going to jail for sure. Like,
we've said so these these kids." He's
like, "What's going on?" I'm like,
"They're not gangsters. They're just
like falling asleep in church." And he's
like, "I've never even been to church."
I was like, "I know." Okay. I We've said
so many things. You choked a kid. Pretty
sure that happened. Okay. Uh I think I
told another kid I'd kill his dog. We've
said so many things. we're going to
prison, you know, we're going to prison
for sure. And he's like, "Dude, I got
this. Don't worry about it. I got this."
And I'm like, "Okay." So, he lines all
the kids up and he's like, "Hey,
everyone, you're reformed." And he's
like, they're like, "Yes, we are
reformed.
Please make it stop." And he's like,
"You're good. You're good. You're all
reformed." And he goes, "Here's the
deal. Uh, if any of you tell anyone
about this ever, we will kill all of
you."
>> Yep.
They were so scared. And so we're
standing there and uh we're like, "Okay,
it's over." So we left. We left that
weekend. I'm like basically wait I just
go home. I'm like I just wait for the
police to come collect me. You know,
going to jail for real. And uh didn't
happen. Two days go by, no jail. Work
with Mike. Two shifts. Never mentions
it. Uh it's been about 10 years now. Not
one of those kids snitched on us. Yeah.
Yeah. Not one of those kids said a
single word to us or to anyone about
anything about us, which is crazy. I'd
like to think a lot of those kids are
12, 13. Okay, it's been about 10 years.
They're very young. Okay, it's it's been
so long. It's been like 10 years now.
And I'd like to think that some of those
kids are like now graduating from Ivy
League schools and they're just like,
"Yeah, once I fell asleep in church and
I got my act together cuz my mom hired
gang members.
One of them choked us. Another one
threatened to kill my dog. I never did
anything wrong again." Thank you so
much, everyone. Wow.
>> All right, let's get into it. Uh, I grew
up in a trailer park to the surprise of
none of you. So,
I don't like that. It's a knowing
laughter. I don't like that. I wish it
was more surprising to people, but you
don't grow up in a house and end up
looking like I do. So, I get it.
I do. You don't even grow up in a double
wide trailer and end up like this. All
single wide right here, baby. That's
right. You had to walk through the
bathroom to get to my bedroom. Okay. I
saw my stepdad pooping a lot. Okay.
a lot of times
very poor. I used to share a bed with my
brother and we used to have a hole in
our bedroom floor we covered with
particle board and a rug and we called
that hole the possum hole
you guessed it cuz there was a possum in
there. Okay,
he didn't even live down there year
round. Okay, our house was not good
enough to be his forever home. All
right.
He was like, "We summer in that trailer.
Winters are rough.
Grew up very poor,
dude." Yeah. Uh, I got older. I did not
get more money. Uh, I have cashed a lot
of checks at Walmart. Okay.
Be real. I thought you guys would be
more of a Walmart check crowd
cuz I can see you with my eyes.
I guess you guys are too good.
Yeah, I used to cash my checks at
Walmart cuz I didn't have a bank account
and then I got one and I was like, I'm
fancy. And then I immediately
overdrafted it a lot.
Some might say too much. And by some I
mean Wells Fargo would say too much. way
too much. So, I couldn't cash my checks
at the bank anymore because they would
take all my money cuz I had overdrafted
it. And then I couldn't cash my checks
at Walmart, you know, on account of them
catching me stealing a TV. So,
do you know that problem we've all had?
Yeah. When you and your brothers get
caught stealing a TV, so you fight the
security guy. And let me tell you, the
police don't care if you win. They will
still arrest you.
No one cares.
So, I grew up in a small town. There's
no cash for gold place. It's Walmart or
the bank. And I was like, well, I can't
use either. So, now I get I like I have
a genius plan. I go, well, I'm going to
open up a new bank account. That'll get
them. So, I went to a different bank and
I was like, I would like to open up a
bank account. And they were like, sir,
right here. Sit down. are opening up the
account and then the other bank is like,
"Hey, it says here you owe Wells Fargo
$400."
And I was like, "You guys know each
other?
I thought you were enemies.
What is this?"
So, I got older and like all trailer
trash hill people, I decided to do
crime,
like as a profession,
a crime that pays better than in TVs.
You know, we're talking about actual
money. How that happened was uh me and
my brothers, we joined a uh a motorcycle
club, which is a cute way of saying a
gang. So
yeah, my stepfather was the sergeant-
in-arms of a motorcycle club and me and
my brothers were like, "That looks
easier than school."
And it was.
So yeah, uh when I was 19 years old, I
was out of my mind and I was a gang
member. I used to fight all the time,
like constantly. And listen, I don't
want anyone here to think I think I'm
tough or anything. That's not what this
is about. It wasn't cool fighting. It's
not like, "Oh, shame, you used to fight
like rival gang members." No. No. I'm
talking about like scrapping with a guy
at PetSmart. Okay. Uh,
like I had a real short fuse. I just saw
a guy give a wrong turtle fact and I was
like, "It's on now.
You are going to catch these hands.
Turtles cannot hold their breath that
long.
And now I am punching you.
I was the worst guy. No one likes that
guy. He's very insecure. The person who
has to solve their problems with
violence. Here was my problem. Okay? I
fought all the time. Now, this is not to
say that I was tough. Listen, a lot of
people see my comedy online and I'll
tell them about my past. Hey, I used to
do crime. I used to be a gang member.
And then they will comment and be like,
this guy isn't tough. He didn't used to
be a gang member. He's like a nerd and a
hipster. Yes.
Yes, I am. I should not have been doing
that.
Me and you both, man. Go back in time
and tell my stepdad not to let me in the
gang. How about that?
I was built for a computer chair, bro.
That's where I want to be. I never
wanted this, dude. I'm not good at
fighting. I didn't even win that many
fights. I don't even like fighting. I
did it because I had a chip on my
shoulder. I was insecure. You have to
understand everyone I grew up around is
the toughest person you've ever heard of
in your life. I'm just like cowboys,
bull riders, outlaws, war heroes.
Everybody I grew up around. Like my
grandfather war hero. Okay. My
stepfather went to prison for murder
multiple times.
They kept letting him out.
Stop letting him out.
They just be like, "Do you promise not
to kill anyone?" And he'd be like,
"Maybe." And they just let him out,
dude. Come on.
It's insane. All right. It's crazy.
Everyone, even my mom, my mom got banned
from Little League games cuz she punched
a guy in the head so hard he said he
went temporarily blind.
We still don't know if he was being
dramatic or if she was just having a
good day. All right. She's like, I'm
limber today,
dude. Terrible. My little brother, my
little brother is 6' 3", like 230 lb,
pure muscle. He is jacked. You know how
people's bodies like send you signals
when you look at them? You're like
receiving a message when you see a
person. When you see my brother, the
message you receive, he's coming to your
village to burn it down. Okay?
If you look at my body, the message
you're receiving is like, "Hey, if
you're nice to me, I might tell you a
story." Like, it's not the same. It's
not the same at all.
If any All my brothers are jacked, dude.
If my brother, one of them, like my
brother takes his shirt off abs, a
woman's going to come out of nowhere and
be like, I should start a life with this
guy.
If I take my shirt off, a dude will pop
up out of nowhere and be like, "Do you
want to play Magic the Gathering with
me?"
Yeah. And I have to be like, "Yes,
I do.
It's not the same
at all.
It sucks."
So, I had a chip on my shoulder, right?
I need to be tough. All these people are
tough. Respect me. So I used to just
fight. If everyone thinks I'm down to
fight all the time, people will think
I'm tough. So that's what I did. One day
I am 19 years old. I am out of my mind
and I'm walking past a wall and on this
wall there's a poster and it is
advertising a martial arts tournament. A
one-day winner takes all no holds barred
martial arts tournament. Like UFC style
death tournament. Okay. I was like,
"That's me right there. Yeah, I'm going
to enter into the tournament. I will
win, I guess, on account of my
tenacity."
It's what I was thinking. And I was
like, "Everyone's going to respect me
now. They're going to know I'm the
realest. This is awesome. This is my
ticket right here to respect." Now, many
of you heard that and you're like,
"That's a terrible plan. If you fight
people who actually know how to fight,
they're going to punch your head off.
and you would be correct.
But it's worse than that because I did
not sign up for a one-day UFC style
death tournament. I accidentally,
without realizing it, signed up for a
one-day pointscoring karate tournament.
For those of you who don't know what
that is, it is not no holds barred. It
is all holds barred. Okay? Pointc
scoring karate is not so much fighting
as a celebration of karate. Okay. Most
of the rule sets don't allow you to
actually punch each other. You tap each
other for points. The referee resets
you. Everyone has a good time. Karate is
fun. Okay. It is not. No holds. You most
people don't even uh punch. It's crazy.
Okay. So, I have signed up thinking it's
a death tournament, but it is pointc
scoring karate. I go and tell my gang
member friends,
yo, I signed up for a one-day UFC style
tournament. Are you guys going to come
support me? And they're like, yes, we
will be there. That sounds amazing.
We will all be there. One of my friends
is like, what division are you going to
fight in? And I was like, they break up
these divisions by belt. I'm gonna fight
in black belt.
He's like, yo, that's crazy cuz you
don't have a black belt. And I was like,
it's not a problem. And it wasn't.
You can just buy a black belt. They're
like, $40. It's incredibly reasonable.
We could all be black belts tonight.
Okay.
No one stops you. No one asks you any
questions. There's no written test. The
guy who sells it to you doesn't even do
one of these to see if you do karate
back at him.
He does it. You're like, he's like,
"That was pretty fast. You can have it."
I'm watching you, though. No, none of
that happens. I went to a store, I
bought a black belt, and the guy who
sold it to me upsold me a pair of
nunchucks. Okay.
that I was later arrested for using.
Now, that's a fun sentence to say. I
bought a black belt and I was sold
nunchucks. But if you stop and think
about what's happening in that
situation, it's so much more insane than
you think. Because here's what's
happening. It is the year 2005. I have
face tattoos in 2005. That's crazy.
Okay? Tattoos were not popular back
then. All right. To have face tattoos
was like that's a gang member. Okay. I
walk up, buy a black belt, like put it
on the thing. He looks at me right in my
stupid tattooed face. Okay. Sees me a
gang member buying a black belt. I did
not earn obviously.
And he thinks to himself,
I'm going to sell this guy nunchucks.
What?
She's like, "Is it morally right to do
this?" No.
Am I going to make the sale and get
those shoes I've been thinking about?
Absolutely I am. I'm like, "What are you
doing?" He literally was like, "Hey, do
you want nunchucks?" And I was like,
"That's allowed. Chuck me up. Let's go."
He goes, "Do you want metal or wood?" I
was like, "You know what I want."
He sold me nunchucks that I was arrested
for using in a bar fight.
That's right. Sounds tough if you don't
think about it.
If you think about it for any amount of
time, it sucks.
It sucks a lot because the implication
of that is that I was in my 20s
going to bars
with nunchucks. Okay,
it's stupid.
I knocked a guy out full on
but he went to sleep.
Sounds tough, but then you have to stop
and think about it really because what
that implies is that my brother and all
my tough biker friends start a like wild
west bar brawl and they're all fighting
like men and then here comes Shane with
nunchucks just like I'm in the Matrix
and you better believe I didn't know how
to use them. Okay. Oh, I read I watched
zero YouTube tutorials. Okay, the fight
started and I was like, "Wait for me,
guys." Trying to get him out of my
pants.
No, I got it. I got it.
I just hurt my hip immediately the
second I
How do they do this?
I I hit a guy so hard, though. They do
work. They do work, though. Woo.
just knocked him out cold. I was
arrested immediately
so fast. I got arrested so fast. It felt
like they were cops were already in the
bar. Like they were waiting for me. Like
it was a kung fu sting or something.
They were just in the bar just like,
"Yeah, Roger. Yeah, it is nunchucks.
No, Roger. Those are nunchucks. Move
in."
Like I thought in my mind I was like I'm
gonna hit everybody with these
nunchucks. I'm gonna hit so many people.
I hit one guy. I hit zero more people.
So I hit him. I was immediately
arrested. And this is why I will never
forget this night for the rest of my
life. Okay. I get arrested super fast.
Now hands behind my back in handcuffs.
The cop is leading me out of the bar
under arrest. one hand on the back of my
neck, the other hand gripping the chain
of the handcuffs, and he is pushing me
out of the bar. And as he's doing it, he
says to the back of my head, he goes,
"Michael Angelo is my favorite."
I was just like, "Am I still in
trouble?"
Oh, yeah. You're super arrested right
now. like you're it's crazy how hard
you're going to jail, dude. I was like,
I just had to ask, you know,
I would love I've always I've told this
story on the road a whole bunch and and
more than anything, I love imagining a
guy in the audience hearing the story
and being like, "Hold on.
Sounds like the time I got hit with
Nunchucks."
Just leaves the showroom, goes into the
lobby with his phone, calls his friend,
his friend answers. He goes, "Shut up.
Shut up right now. Do you remember in
2005 when I got knocked out in that
fight and everyone made fun of me cuz I
said I got hit with nunchucks and all of
you guys were like, "No one brings
nunchucks to the bar. You got knocked
out regular." Well, he's here right now.
No, I don't know if he has nunchucks on
him.
So,
oh man. So, I have a black belt now,
right?
and I'm ready for the fight.
So, here's what happened. So, I have my
black belt, but the fight isn't for
several days. I signed up and you know,
I have to wait for the tournament. Now,
I don't know if you guys can know by
just looking at me, but I'm not a big
consequences guy, okay? I don't think
about them. Consequences, those are
future Shane's problems, okay?
That guy hates us.
But we don't care what he thinks, do we?
We're out here living.
So, I signed up for this tournament and
I do begin to develop anxiety. I'm not
used to waiting for a fight. Now, don't
forget, I do believe I've signed up for
a one-day UFC style tournament. And I'm
freaking out because I'm like, "Okay,
well, I have confidence in myself." But
these guys are like the best guys.
They're black belts. Those are the best
fighters right now. I'm like, "What if
they knock me out? What if they beat me
up? What if they humiliate me in front
of my friends? I'm I'm going crazy. I
have all this anxiety. I can't sleep.
I'm obsessing. The day of the fights
come and I'm so nervous. I'm so racked
with anxiety that I am not perceiving
the world around me as I walk into a
high school gymnasium. Okay.
Surrounded by children. All right. It is
like noon on Saturday. This is not the
time for a UFC style death tournament.
But that's not occurring to me. Okay.
I'm literally in a gym like in a
basketball court with the wrestling mats
laid out. Okay. There's people all over.
In my mind, I'm so nervous that I'm just
like, "Yeah, kids fight to the death,
too.
Karate's crazy like that.
I'm losing it, man. I'm so nervous. I
send my gang member friends into the
bleachers with the moms."
Mhm. And I sign in. I'm completely
focused just looking at the Matt. You
can do this, Shane. You can do this,
Shane. I'm I'm freaking out. They
announce the first pairing over the
loudspeaker. They're just like, "First
up in the black belt division, we've got
Shane Smith versus Sensei Dan." It's
like the sensei,
right? That's the best guy. I was like,
"Why am I fighting the final boss? That
doesn't make sense. You don't do that
first. I should fight three
progressively bigger guys and every time
I beat them I get some fruit and that
makes me healthier
or something to fight the best guy cuz
in my mind the sensei is the best guy
right he's the sensei what I am not
realizing at the time is that every guy
in this tournament is a sensei they all
own karate schools all these children
are their students why else would an
adult be here.
But I don't know that.
I'm like, Dan's the sensei. He's the
guy. This place is so casual and
everyone's having so much fun with each
other. They didn't even call him by his
last name. They called him Sensei Dan.
That doesn't occur to me. I'm just like,
well, Dan's the ultimate warrior.
I walk into the circle to get ready for
the fight. All right, I'm here. The
referee's here. Dan comes out and I see
him for the first time. Now, I can only
describe Dan as like, if you guys ever
seen Mike Wazowski from Monsters, Inc.,
you know that, guys?
All right.
Now, I would never body shame someone.
Okay? Truly, from the bottom of my
heart, if you are living your life and
you're happy and killing it, I'm happy
and proud for you. You keep doing that.
Well, let's all be real with each other.
Some bodies are not karate bodies, okay?
Dan did not exactly have a body for
karate. Okay, but that's not what I
thought when I saw him. I was so amped
up and so nervous that as soon as I saw
him, my first thought was, "Well, that's
what the ultimate warrior looks like.
Crazy. All his muscle is in the middle
of him like that.
You've seen this before. It's a He could
probably deadlift 800 lb. That's a power
belly. That's what that is.
Dan walks up to me and we are facing off
for the fight. Dan is wearing eyelasses
for the fight.
Now, in pointc scoring karate, you can't
punch someone in the face.
So, he's safe to wear glasses,
but I don't know that.
I see my man wearing eyelasses for a
fist fight and I'm just like, "Wow, you
don't think I can hit you in the face?
You're so confident that you're going to
matrix pass all my punches?
You wore glasses for the fight?"
Another level of confidence. It makes me
nervous immediately. I'm just like,
"This guy thinks he's going to knock me
out before I could touch his glasses.
This is crazy. I'm losing my mind." The
referee's like, "Are you ready?" "Yeah."
"Are you ready?" "Yeah." And he's about
to tell us to fight. Dan and I are
existing in two separate realities
simultaneously.
Okay.
Dan is here smiling away at the pointc
scoring karate tournament.
to have fun with his friends and family.
I am at the Mortal Kombat tournament,
fighting for my life.
So the referee says, "Fight." And dude,
before his hand is even all the way
down, I am attacking Dan like a wild
animal.
Right? Cuz how do you beat the best guy?
You got to go right at him.
I can't fight him on his terms. That's
crazy. He's a master.
So my plan is this. I go, "Well, Dan's
the best guy. He's a karate master. He's
the sensei. So I'm going to throw like
nine strikes in a row at him, and he
will casually block all of them.
But maybe one gets through, and that is
my ticket to victory. I'm going to
overwhelm him. I'm going to surprise him
with my confidence and aggression. So
that's what I do, dude. The left hand
isn't even all the way down and I am
attacking him like a maniac.
The first strike I throw at Dan, big
kick. Dan does not block it
and in fact chooses to absorb all of it
into his stomach.
And then he takes a step back, doubles
over, and made a sound I've never heard
since.
He sounded like a whale got the wind
knocked out of it. He just went
and then from this position, he chose to
lay on the ground.
So I'm standing there just like caught
sensei Dan slipping. Nice. Right. Got
him. And I'm looking at him on the
ground and the ref walks up and the ref
goes, "Don't look at him. Turn around."
I was like, "What is happening?" He
goes, "Turn around. Don't look at him."
And I was like, "I don't know what's
happening." And he goes, "Don't look at
him. Turn around." And I was like,
"What? Like he's a Medusa?" And I put my
hand over my eyes.
The referee physically grabs me and
turns me around. I was like, "Yo, dude.
Are we fighting from behind right now?
What is happening?
So, for those of you who are wondering
what's happening in pointc scoring
karate, if you hurt your opponent or
they like fall down, in this rule set,
you're supposed to know, oh, they fell
down and immediately turn around and
like kneel and look away so that your
opponent has space and time to regain
their composure
with dignity. Okay.
But what I did
was kick my man in the stomach pretty
hard. Okay.
And then he laid on the ground riving
and I just looked at him like, "What
now, Dad?"
And the ref was like, "Turn around." And
I put my hand over my eyes
like his pants had popped off.
[Applause]
Now, it is fair to say at this point,
they know I'm not a black belt. Okay,
so the ref turns me back around and to
Dan's credit, he's up and he wants to
keep fighting. Dan is about that action.
Okay, now this is the worst thing that
can happen to me because don't forget,
nothing has broke my illusion that Dan
is the best guy. I just think my
strategy worked and I got him. But I
didn't stop him. He wants to keep
fighting and now he's angry.
I have awoken the dragon that lives
inside Sensei Dan.
He's going to super move me and I'm
going to die, right? He's going to
hadukan me or something. It's going to
quarter circle forward B and it's over.
So,
I'm standing there and the guy's like,
"Are you ready to fight?" And I'm like,
"Yeah." He goes, "Dan, are you ready to
fight?" Dan's like, "Yeah." And then he
says, "Fight." Before his hand is even
down, I'm jumping the gun again. I'm
jumping away from Dan as far as I can to
the edge of the circle. I can't be on
the attack twice. That's not how that
works. I'm on the defense. I jump away
from Dan like the minute I can. Dan, I
think, wanted revenge because he tried
to kick me doing some Karate Kid jumping
thing. But because I was already jumping
away from him, his jumping kick whiffs
completely
and then he falls forward towards me.
Foot forward, head down. Because don't
forget, big on top, small on bottom.
All right. So now he's down, bent down,
head towards me, arms back like he's
Naruto running. Okay.
Now in point scoring karate, you are not
allowed to punch someone in the head.
So arms back, head towards me, that's
fine.
But I don't know that
I see Dan's head lined up like a T-ball.
And I do what any of you would have
done.
And I was just like, "United States of
America." And I punched him in the head
as hard as I could.
Dan's glasses explode off of his body
and he goes to sleep.
He goes the whole way. I have knocked
him out. I have starched Sensei Dan.
All right. He is fully out. I didn't
even knock him out regular style. He got
knocked out Looney Tune style. Okay. You
know when someone gets knocked out so
hard they go rigid first like I'm a tree
and then they go to sleep like he was
down like this and then he went straight
up like a board wy coyote and then he
went down. I distinctly remember looking
at him on the ground being like hm I
killed sensei Dan.
Interesting.
So some lady yells right away. She's
like, "Get away from him." Some guy's
like, "Tan, are you okay?" And I'm just
standing there like, "Did I win or what?
I don't know the rules."
So, you would think hundreds of people
in this gym, right, that I just knocked
Dan out. A lady is yelling at me. Every
eye in this gym should be on me and Dan.
But not one person is looking at us. No
one in this gym is looking at us. Every
eye, hundreds of people is looking
directly at the bleachers where I
realize I left my gang member friends
who just watched me win a fight by
knockout
and they are losing their minds.
Dude, just full grown men with face
tattoos surrounded by moms screaming
like they're powering up in Dragon Ball
Z. Just a
losing it, dude. One of my friends just
grabbing a child by a shirt like, "You
seen this?"
Someone jumped over the bleachers,
walked onto the wrestling mats wearing
his boots, took his shirt off, and was
like, "Who else wants the smoke?"
People were like, "It's not a group
thing." He was like, "It could be
though."
To just one of my friends in a random
mom's face WWE style like
Like, bro, she's not a part of this.
What are you doing?
So,
I was banned from karate forever.
And I was just like, tough but fair,
right? That makes sense.
So, I had I had to go gather up my
friends and they're just I was like, I'm
banned. And they were like, is that our
fault? Team effort. That was all of us.
This was a us thing, not a me thing.
All right.
And uh honestly, can I be real with you
guys? I think being banned from karate
is cooler than having a black belt.
Okay. Yeah. Yeah. That's right.
You are correct to cheer.
That's right. People are just like, "Do
you have a black belt?" No. Not allowed
to do karate.
Too powerful.
Yeah, I know the secret technique they
don't want you to know. It's called
punching a guy in the head with all your
might. That's what that's called.
So, I left, you know, I had to leave.
So, as I'm walking out, I'm like, "I'm
so sorry, Dan." And he's on the
stretcher giving me the Terminator thumb
like, "It's cool. I'm good."
Like, "All right, sorry, everyone. I
don't know the rules." People are like,
"We are aware.
I was just like, "But I signed waivers,
so I'm good to leave." They were like,
"You can't leave fast enough. Get out of
here, man." I was like, "All right, my
bad." And I was like, "And I'm banned
for life." They're like, "Never come
back." I was like, "Do you want to like
write something down or take a photo of
me?" And they were like, "No, we will
remember you."
Thanks so much, everyone. I had so much
fun with you guys.
Oh,
[Applause]
[Music]
heat.